<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Miao Yu | 于淼 </title>
    <link>/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Miao Yu | 于淼 </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get rid of bibliography with R</title>
      <link>/en/2018/01/12/get-rid-of-bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2018/01/12/get-rid-of-bibliography/</guid>
      <description>Change citation and bibliography format for papers are somewhat waste of time when we are not really care about the contents about how to order the authors, journal and issues. To be honest, with the popularity of HTML support on most of the journal, citation in the paper could always be linked to the original webpage via DOI. In those cases, extra bibliography just make the papers longer and require extra efforts to covert the items of interests into the original paper webpages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow-up based open source journal</title>
      <link>/en/2017/12/17/blockchain-based-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/12/17/blockchain-based-journal/</guid>
      <description>Dose peer reviews really fit into this era? I have been a reviewer for few times and recently such idea come into my minds. My answer would be NO.
Almost all of the studies are from N to N+1 instead of 0 to 1. That’s why we need peer reviews to strength new findings and hypothesis. However, peer reviews actually happens everyday before and after the paper get published. Most of the research group would have some kinds of journal talk or literature reading to introduce new study for other group members or train the skills for presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real high-throughput for LC/GC-MS</title>
      <link>/en/2017/07/09/real-high-throughput-for-lc-gc-ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/07/09/real-high-throughput-for-lc-gc-ms/</guid>
      <description>If someone want to know whether some compounds exist in certain samples. He always need to make pretreatment for that samples and make them into a little vial for analysis in sophisticated instruments like mass spectrum. If you want to analysis many components in one sample, you also need some separation methods like gas/liquid chromatography. How about analysis multiple samples and multiple compounds in a single run?
Pseudo high-throughput If you use LC/GC-MS to analysis samples, all the efforts for high-throughput would be limited at the injection step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text mining for top academic journals</title>
      <link>/en/2017/07/07/text-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/07/07/text-mining/</guid>
      <description>Text mining is often used to find spatiotemporal trends in news, government report and user generated contents in SNS websites. We could make sentiment analysis to find the real opinions of netizens. Also we could track the popularity of certain phases and find the connections among them. Such technique might also be useful for scientists or researchers to read papers.
Scientists or researchers’ daily life is immersed by a lot of literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selection of open source software platform for metabolomics or lipidomics</title>
      <link>/en/2017/06/12/selection-of-software-platform-for-metabolomics-or-lipidomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/06/12/selection-of-software-platform-for-metabolomics-or-lipidomics/</guid>
      <description>Recently I reviewed some platforms for metabolomics or lipidomics and tried to find out which one is currently available to my demands. I knew some instrumental company supplied software or solutions for metabolomics and lipidomics. I just disliked them since they concealed too many details about data processing which made omics studies as a magic box like Artificial Neural Network. It gains nothing for scientist to get insights from the data and you might only follow the workflow defined by the company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data analysis for Desorption Electrospray Ionization</title>
      <link>/en/2017/05/11/data-analysis-for-desorption-electrospray-ionization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/05/11/data-analysis-for-desorption-electrospray-ionization/</guid>
      <description>Desorption Electrospray Ionization (DESI) is known for on-site mass spectrum analysis. For example, you could use DESI-MS to get the distribution of certain ions on the surface or cross section of sample. Without chromatograph or related separation process, the mass spectrum is actually the average intensities of all the mass during the sampling time. Recently I am thinking how to process such data via xcms.
Supposing we have data from 1 min sampling and we want to get the mass spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using xcms offline for metabolomics study</title>
      <link>/en/2017/05/02/using-xcms-offline-for-metabolomics-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/05/02/using-xcms-offline-for-metabolomics-study/</guid>
      <description>XCMS online is preferred for its convenience, especially with Stream. However, the storage is limited and you need to wait for some time to process your data. Actually, almost all of the functions online could be processed offline on local computer. Here I will show you some tips about using xcms package locally in R.
Optimized Parameters Most of the users like xcms online because they have optimized parameters for different instruments and you could directly choose them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for local installation of MetaboAnalyst on Windows</title>
      <link>/en/2017/03/29/metaboanalyst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/03/29/metaboanalyst/</guid>
      <description>I am running Windows 7 to perform metabolomics data analysis(mainly for mscovert). Recently I found MetaboAnalyst could be installed locally. Since some group members really care about their data safety, I just installed MetaboAnalyst on one of group computers. Here is some tips for it:
 Windows 7 is currently not supported by Metaboanalyst, so I use virtualbox to install a 64-bit Ubuntu 16.10.
 For Ubuntu, you need to install a few packages to support both the R and Java environment, also some packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical uncertainty of Isotope Ratio</title>
      <link>/en/2017/01/15/sd-isotope-ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/01/15/sd-isotope-ratio/</guid>
      <description>In Analytical Chemistry, the measurements of isotope ratios are commons. However, I found the uncertainty of ratios are always shown in the format of standard deviation of independant vairiable, which is inappropriate in statistic. You accually measure at least two values to get one measurement.
In fact, if you want to use the differences of isotope ratios as a measurement for certain process, you need to accept the assumption that the intensities of different isotopes are independant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation and reduction of the analytical uncertainties in GC-MS analysis using a boundary regression model</title>
      <link>/en/2016/11/29/my-third-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2016/11/29/my-third-paper/</guid>
      <description>This paper received opposite comments from reviewers. One rejected and the other recommanded. Anyway, this is just the beginning of this kind of data analysis for mass spectrum. Also this work was the basis of one chapter in my thesis.
In this work, I wanted to access and reduce the uncertainties in the whole procedure of environmental analysis. In regular analysis, we would use pure standards to optimized the analysis method and recovery and RSD were commonly used for quality control analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Chinese in RStudio Beamer Slides</title>
      <link>/en/2016/09/19/beamer-in-chinese/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2016/09/19/beamer-in-chinese/</guid>
      <description>RStudio is an excellent IDE for R. However, using Chinese in default setting of Rmd to output a PDF document is always annoying. Well, the source is tex. RStudio uses knitr to covert the Rmd document into md document. Then it uses Pandoc to convert the md document into tex document. Then they actually use tex engine such as pdflatex or xelatex to get PDF document. Why Chinese would not</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic idea behind cluster analysis</title>
      <link>/en/2016/09/11/basic-idea-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2016/09/11/basic-idea-cluster/</guid>
      <description>After we got a lot of samples and analyzed the concentrations of many compounds in them, we may ask about the relationship between the samples. You might have the sampling information such as the date and the position and you could use boxplot or violin plot to explore the relationships among those categorical variables. However, you could also use the data to find some potential relationship.
But how? if two samples&amp;rsquo; data were almost the same, we might think those samples were from the same potential group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic idea behind principal components analysis</title>
      <link>/en/2016/08/31/basic-idea-pca/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2016/08/31/basic-idea-pca/</guid>
      <description>For environmental scientist, data analysis might be the only way to show your ability when you get the data from observation. I found many students even researcher showed their data in a bad way and many data analysis pattern just came from certain one paper. However, data analysis methods always have their scopes and some methods might just not suit your cases.
Thanks to data analysis software, you need not to calculate some values by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolomics workflow in Rstudio</title>
      <link>/en/2016/08/21/meta-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2016/08/21/meta-workflow/</guid>
      <description>I have moved to Canada for about three weeks. Now I am a PostDoc in University of Waterloo. I will handle two projects about in silica studies in analytical chemistry. Well, I treated them as another data and modeling-driven interdisciplinary studies.
The first step is building the data analysis envrionment for group members. Since I could set down such envrionment on a super computer with RAM 128 GB, I preferred to use R and xcms for metabolomics data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structure Prediction of Methyoxy-polybrominated diphenyls ethers (MeO-PBDEs) through GC-MS analysis of their corresponding PBDEs</title>
      <link>/en/2016/02/11/my-second-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2016/02/11/my-second-paper/</guid>
      <description>This is a paper with many rejection and comments. It was finally published by Talanta with DOI 10.1016/j.talanta.2016.01.047. One study said the average read times of an academic paper was no more than 3. In my case, at least 11 reviewers had read this paper before published and I thanked all of them though some of them really misunderstand my idea.
The basic idea before the structure prediction is that the combination of two qualitative methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPLC 2015 Beijing</title>
      <link>/en/2015/09/30/hplc-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2015/09/30/hplc-2015/</guid>
      <description>Last week 43rd International Symposium on High Performance Liquid Phase Separations and Related Techniques(HPLC 2015 Beijing) was held at the Beijing International Conference Center in Beijing, China. For my tutor was the chair of this conference, I stayed there for three days and made a poster presentation. Here is some tips from the HPLC 2015 Beijing.
 &amp;ldquo;NMR is your mother, MS is your love and the LC is your superhero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Data Analysis Similarity between Microarray and GC-MS</title>
      <link>/en/2015/09/11/microarry-vs-ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2015/09/11/microarry-vs-ms/</guid>
      <description>I have finished Data Analysis for Genomics(HarvardX-PH525x) by Prof. Rafael A Irizarry and Dr. Michael I Love for more than a year until recently I realised the data analysis similarity between microarray and Gas chromatography–mass spectrometry(GC-MS).
When we talked about data analysis of microarray, we use different genes or probes as the rows and different samples as the columns. The responses are fluorescence signals.
When we talked about data analysis of microarray, we use different m/z as the rows and different retention times as the columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to deal with the less than obvious?</title>
      <link>/en/2015/09/05/loq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2015/09/05/loq/</guid>
      <description>In environmental analysis, we often target a lot of compounds to get a detailed profile of certain pollution. However, due to different environmental process, not all of the compounds could be detected by our analysis method. For example, when I analysed PBDEs in 100 sludge samples, only a few congeners such as BDE-47, BDE-99, BDE-209 could be found in all of them. The other congerners such as BDE-28, BDE-17, BDE-153 could only be found in about 80% of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISOTOPES 2015</title>
      <link>/en/2015/06/30/isotopes-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2015/06/30/isotopes-2015/</guid>
      <description>I went to Israel at the late June for Isotopes 2015 conference. This is my first time trip abroad and it is my pleasure to visit Jerusalem and make friends with scholars from all over the world. This is a quick note of some important tips about isotopes 2015.
 Thank you, all of the organisers of the conference!
 Thank you, all of the participants and I learned a lot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to SP-ICP-MS</title>
      <link>/en/2015/01/03/intro-sp-icp-ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2015/01/03/intro-sp-icp-ms/</guid>
      <description>Single particle Inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry(SP-ICP-MS) is a novol method for detect, quantify, and characterize nanoparticles. Its theoretical basis was founded by Dr. Degueldre et al. at 2004. Here I would like to show a much more simplified version of this theory and show you how to perform a SP-ICP-MS analysis.
Single Particle The core concept in SP-ICP-MS is single particle. How to understand single particle? Single means every scan time on MS would get no more than one particle&amp;rsquo;s signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using recommender systems to fill the missing data</title>
      <link>/en/2014/11/26/recommender-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2014/11/26/recommender-system/</guid>
      <description>Recommender systems were often used to show the candidates such as books, movies and music for certain user. If you bought something at online shop, you might get a spam email listing something the shop recommended and there must be a recommender systems for you. You might get confused by such system: how does they know what you would buy?
If you know basic concepts about machine learning, you might say: surely there would be a supervised learning algorithm for this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display Chinese/Japanese/Korean in PDF from Rmd in RStudio</title>
      <link>/en/2014/07/21/rmd-to-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2014/07/21/rmd-to-pdf/</guid>
      <description>New RStudio shows many useful features to make dynamic documents. We could write Rmd and output word document and PDF. However, when I try to write Chinese in Rmd and convert it into PDF, the Chinese characters is missing. @Yihui added a new feature fig.showtext which allow us to show Chinese in the plot. Still, the Chinese words in the content are missing. I refer to a lot of posts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using rcdk package for QSPR</title>
      <link>/en/2014/05/30/qspr-rcdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2014/05/30/qspr-rcdk/</guid>
      <description>R is a handy tool for modeling, so there must be some packages for Quantitative structure–activity relationship(QSPR) in Chemistry. Recently I wanted to summarize some papers for a presentation, then I found rcdk package, which is a useful tool for QSPR. However, little posts about this topic for beginner. As an absolutely beginner, I make this post as a note for the whole process and add comments for someone else to reproduce a QSPR model by their own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A very brief intro of shiny</title>
      <link>/en/2014/03/23/intro-of-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2014/03/23/intro-of-shiny/</guid>
      <description>If you are a starter of shiny as me, this post may help your know some principle of shiny.
 What is shiny?  R based View as webpage hosted on servers give a request, show the result  Backgroud needed  Almost R only  Why shiny?  Entirely extensible Display your data in an interactive way  How shiny works?  Reactive Programming
When the input changes, the R code will run again to get a refresh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mean, Variance and Something about Sample</title>
      <link>/en/2013/12/07/mean-and-variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/12/07/mean-and-variance/</guid>
      <description>OK，I must clear the concepts of those terms because this is the third time I review my notes.
Description of Data If one wants to descript a collection of data, the Mode, Median and Mean are the first three terms to be learned. They are used to show the whole data in one parameter. And yes, one value is enough and the most important property of a dataset is the center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolites of 2,4,4′-Tribrominated Diphenyl Ether (BDE-28) in Pumpkin after In Vivo and In Vitro Exposure</title>
      <link>/en/2013/12/04/my-first-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/12/04/my-first-paper/</guid>
      <description>This is the first paper written by me which was just published on Environmental Science &amp;amp; Technology, pp 13494–13501, Volume 47, Issue 23, 2013. You could access the full text either by ACS&amp;rsquo;s website or just send Dr. Liu or me an email.
This work focused on the metabolites of BDE-28 in plant. The main finding is that after the exposure, BDE-28 could be transformed to OH-diBDEs, OH-triBDEs and MeO-triBDEs. Without the standards of metabolites, the MeO-triBDEs were identified as para-MeO-triBDE by thumb rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Halogen Bond for separation</title>
      <link>/en/2013/10/10/halogen-bond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/10/10/halogen-bond/</guid>
      <description>As shown in wikipedia, the Halogen bond is the non-covalent interaction that occurs between a halogen atom (Lewis acid) and a Lewis base. The Hydrogen bond could be seen as a special case of halogen bond — they all need electron-donor while the hydrogen may also need electron-receptor. In fact, some Organic Halogen Compounds such as PCBs, PBDEs,PFCs,SCCPs&amp;hellip; were hard to analysis for they have so many congeners. Most of time, the capillary columns were used to separate those compounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal Inference with Confounding Factors</title>
      <link>/en/2013/09/02/causal-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/09/02/causal-inference/</guid>
      <description>Recently I read some articles about causal interpretations. I was told that the correlation doesn&amp;rsquo;t imply causation the first time I learned it. Also the Simpson&amp;rsquo;s paradox show that some confounding factors may destroy the conclusion based on the whole. Maybe when someone wanted to use the cor relationship to do the causal inference, the first problem is the evaluation of the effect of confounding factors.
Here, we must know the confounding factors are not the interaction between the variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Box Plot v.s. Violin Plot</title>
      <link>/en/2013/08/15/boxplot-vs-violinplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/08/15/boxplot-vs-violinplot/</guid>
      <description>In a seminar I introduced the violin plot and showed the following figure(this example comes from the help document):
library(vioplot) library(sm) par(mfrow = c(1, 2)) mu &amp;lt;- 2 si &amp;lt;- 0.6 bimodal &amp;lt;- c(rnorm(1000, -mu, si), rnorm(1000, mu, si)) uniform &amp;lt;- runif(1000, -4, 4) normal &amp;lt;- rnorm(2000, 0, 3) vioplot(bimodal, uniform, normal) boxplot(bimodal, uniform, normal)  So obviously, the violin plot can show more information than box plot. When we perform an exploratory analysis, nothing about the samples could be known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Log Transformation of Concentration Data</title>
      <link>/en/2013/06/19/statistics-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/06/19/statistics-tips/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I read Part I of Song S. Qian&amp;rsquo;s book - Environmental and Ecological Statistics with R and find some interesting tips about statistics in environmental science. Here I will discuss the log transformation of concentration.
In this book, the author said that the statistical distribution of concentration data of certain compounds need a log transformation to show a bell curve. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this conclusion comes from certain theory or just depends on the observation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SNS Websites in China</title>
      <link>/en/2013/06/08/cloned-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/06/08/cloned-websites/</guid>
      <description>If you find a Chinese blog, you may confused by so many unknown icons at the share buttons. You may want to know the daily life of Chinese and only to find the Chinese on the Facebook are also lived in you country. Here, I think you need to know something about the network in China.
 Great Firewall  He who does not reach the Great Wall is not a man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Introduction of Nomograph</title>
      <link>/en/2013/06/03/nomograph-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/06/03/nomograph-intro/</guid>
      <description>Before I know something about the geometry, the mathematics equals algebra. Algebra is really an art of abstract while the geometry will bring you back to real life. In other word, maths doesn&amp;rsquo;t always mean an accurate calculation with each steps clearly. Don&amp;rsquo;t panic, I mean sometimes we will get the answer just like a magic. The nomogragh is a typically skill to get an answer of equations without analytic solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Data</title>
      <link>/en/2013/05/27/my-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/05/27/my-data/</guid>
      <description>After a travel to Henan province, I found my removable disk is broken. I don&amp;rsquo;t know when it happened but it just happened. Two days ago, Dropbox pushed an email to remind me of using it, then I find it is hard to record the data in dropbox from my memory. I got so many data that I can&amp;rsquo;t find one when I need it, so I just got more data from the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rules of Ignoring</title>
      <link>/en/2013/05/24/rules-of-ignoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/05/24/rules-of-ignoring/</guid>
      <description>If I&amp;rsquo;d like to keep on writing this pages for such a long time, the new readers will find it&amp;rsquo;s hard to figure out something about me by so many articles. In fact, if I find a guy&amp;rsquo;s post interesting, I will try to read the other posts in his blog. But most of the time, I am confused by so many tags and classification and I will drop. So for most of the viewers as you, this posts will be just ignored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cipher Based on Similar Pictures</title>
      <link>/en/2013/05/23/pic-cipher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/05/23/pic-cipher/</guid>
      <description>After I finished the computational photography on the coursera, I finally know some basic principles about the digital pictures. The peer-viewed assignment which focused on the epsilon photography is very interesting. In fact, I know nothing about this term before but when I take some photos, I found it awesome to perform something interesting. Recently, Google plus showed a new feature named auto awesome, which is a good application of epsilon photography; but I want to talk about using similar photos to hide some information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HELLO WORLD!</title>
      <link>/en/2013/05/20/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/05/20/hello-world/</guid>
      <description> italic bold
italic bold
Header 1 Header 2 Header 3 Header 4  Item 1 Item 2 Item 3  Item 3a Item 3b   http://example.com
linked phrase
A friend once said:
 It&amp;rsquo;s always better to give than to receive.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>