<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paper on Miao Yu | 于淼 </title>
    <link>/tags/paper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paper on Miao Yu | 于淼 </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation and reduction of the analytical uncertainties in GC-MS analysis using a boundary regression model</title>
      <link>/en/2016/11/29/my-third-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2016/11/29/my-third-paper/</guid>
      <description>This paper received opposite comments from reviewers. One rejected and the other recommanded. Anyway, this is just the beginning of this kind of data analysis for mass spectrum. Also this work was the basis of one chapter in my thesis.
In this work, I wanted to access and reduce the uncertainties in the whole procedure of environmental analysis. In regular analysis, we would use pure standards to optimized the analysis method and recovery and RSD were commonly used for quality control analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structure Prediction of Methyoxy-polybrominated diphenyls ethers (MeO-PBDEs) through GC-MS analysis of their corresponding PBDEs</title>
      <link>/en/2016/02/11/my-second-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2016/02/11/my-second-paper/</guid>
      <description>This is a paper with many rejection and comments. It was finally published by Talanta with DOI 10.1016/j.talanta.2016.01.047. One study said the average read times of an academic paper was no more than 3. In my case, at least 11 reviewers had read this paper before published and I thanked all of them though some of them really misunderstand my idea.
The basic idea before the structure prediction is that the combination of two qualitative methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolites of 2,4,4′-Tribrominated Diphenyl Ether (BDE-28) in Pumpkin after In Vivo and In Vitro Exposure</title>
      <link>/en/2013/12/04/my-first-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/12/04/my-first-paper/</guid>
      <description>This is the first paper written by me which was just published on Environmental Science &amp;amp; Technology, pp 13494–13501, Volume 47, Issue 23, 2013. You could access the full text either by ACS&amp;rsquo;s website or just send Dr. Liu or me an email.
This work focused on the metabolites of BDE-28 in plant. The main finding is that after the exposure, BDE-28 could be transformed to OH-diBDEs, OH-triBDEs and MeO-triBDEs. Without the standards of metabolites, the MeO-triBDEs were identified as para-MeO-triBDE by thumb rules.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>