<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Miao Yu | 于淼 </title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Miao Yu | 于淼 </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Use docker to package your metabolomics study</title>
      <link>/en/2018/01/17/use-docker-to-package-your-metabolomics-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2018/01/17/use-docker-to-package-your-metabolomics-study/</guid>
      <description>One of the most annoying thing during data analysis is that the technique barrier between the authors and the users. For example, you could share your raw data, script and reports online while other people just can’t reproduce your results. Actually, the development environment matters.
If you have developed some software, you must know that we just can’t build an application from the very beginning and dependencies are always needed. Some of them could be distributed with the system software, while the others must be installed yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get rid of bibliography with R</title>
      <link>/en/2018/01/12/get-rid-of-bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2018/01/12/get-rid-of-bibliography/</guid>
      <description>Change citation and bibliography format for papers are somewhat waste of time when we are not really care about the contents about how to order the authors, journal and issues. To be honest, with the popularity of HTML support on most of the journal, citation in the paper could always be linked to the original webpage via DOI. In those cases, extra bibliography just make the papers longer and require extra efforts to covert the items of interests into the original paper webpages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DOI 年代的参考文献</title>
      <link>/cn/2018/01/11/doi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cn/2018/01/11/doi/</guid>
      <description>现在的研究人员其实大部分时间都浪费在了研究完全不沾边的事，例如论文排版，而论文排版中的大部分时间其实是花费在了按照期刊要求改格式。我个人有个</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text mining for top academic journals</title>
      <link>/en/2017/07/07/text-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/07/07/text-mining/</guid>
      <description>Text mining is often used to find spatiotemporal trends in news, government report and user generated contents in SNS websites. We could make sentiment analysis to find the real opinions of netizens. Also we could track the popularity of certain phases and find the connections among them. Such technique might also be useful for scientists or researchers to read papers.
Scientists or researchers’ daily life is immersed by a lot of literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display Chinese/Japanese/Korean in PDF from Rmd in RStudio</title>
      <link>/en/2014/07/21/rmd-to-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2014/07/21/rmd-to-pdf/</guid>
      <description>New RStudio shows many useful features to make dynamic documents. We could write Rmd and output word document and PDF. However, when I try to write Chinese in Rmd and convert it into PDF, the Chinese characters is missing. @Yihui added a new feature fig.showtext which allow us to show Chinese in the plot. Still, the Chinese words in the content are missing. I refer to a lot of posts</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using rcdk package for QSPR</title>
      <link>/en/2014/05/30/qspr-rcdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2014/05/30/qspr-rcdk/</guid>
      <description>R is a handy tool for modeling, so there must be some packages for Quantitative structure–activity relationship(QSPR) in Chemistry. Recently I wanted to summarize some papers for a presentation, then I found rcdk package, which is a useful tool for QSPR. However, little posts about this topic for beginner. As an absolutely beginner, I make this post as a note for the whole process and add comments for someone else to reproduce a QSPR model by their own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A very brief intro of shiny</title>
      <link>/en/2014/03/23/intro-of-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2014/03/23/intro-of-shiny/</guid>
      <description>If you are a starter of shiny as me, this post may help your know some principle of shiny.
 What is shiny?  R based View as webpage hosted on servers give a request, show the result  Backgroud needed  Almost R only  Why shiny?  Entirely extensible Display your data in an interactive way  How shiny works?  Reactive Programming
When the input changes, the R code will run again to get a refresh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Box Plot v.s. Violin Plot</title>
      <link>/en/2013/08/15/boxplot-vs-violinplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2013/08/15/boxplot-vs-violinplot/</guid>
      <description>In a seminar I introduced the violin plot and showed the following figure(this example comes from the help document):
library(vioplot) library(sm) par(mfrow = c(1, 2)) mu &amp;lt;- 2 si &amp;lt;- 0.6 bimodal &amp;lt;- c(rnorm(1000, -mu, si), rnorm(1000, mu, si)) uniform &amp;lt;- runif(1000, -4, 4) normal &amp;lt;- rnorm(2000, 0, 3) vioplot(bimodal, uniform, normal) boxplot(bimodal, uniform, normal)  So obviously, the violin plot can show more information than box plot. When we perform an exploratory analysis, nothing about the samples could be known.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>