<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metabolomics on Miao Yu | 于淼 </title>
    <link>/tags/metabolomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Metabolomics on Miao Yu | 于淼 </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/metabolomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Real high-throughput for LC/GC-MS</title>
      <link>/en/2017/07/09/real-high-throughput-for-lc-gc-ms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/07/09/real-high-throughput-for-lc-gc-ms/</guid>
      <description>If someone want to know whether some compounds exist in certain samples. He always need to make pretreatment for that samples and make them into a little vial for analysis in sophisticated instruments like mass spectrum. If you want to analysis many components in one sample, you also need some separation methods like gas/liquid chromatography. How about analysis multiple samples and multiple compounds in a single run?
Pseudo high-throughput If you use LC/GC-MS to analysis samples, all the efforts for high-throughput would be limited at the injection step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selection of open source software platform for metabolomics or lipidomics</title>
      <link>/en/2017/06/12/selection-of-software-platform-for-metabolomics-or-lipidomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/06/12/selection-of-software-platform-for-metabolomics-or-lipidomics/</guid>
      <description>Recently I reviewed some platforms for metabolomics or lipidomics and tried to find out which one is currently available to my demands. I knew some instrumental company supplied software or solutions for metabolomics and lipidomics. I just disliked them since they concealed too many details about data processing which made omics studies as a magic box like Artificial Neural Network. It gains nothing for scientist to get insights from the data and you might only follow the workflow defined by the company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data analysis for Desorption Electrospray Ionization</title>
      <link>/en/2017/05/11/data-analysis-for-desorption-electrospray-ionization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/05/11/data-analysis-for-desorption-electrospray-ionization/</guid>
      <description>Desorption Electrospray Ionization (DESI) is known for on-site mass spectrum analysis. For example, you could use DESI-MS to get the distribution of certain ions on the surface or cross section of sample. Without chromatograph or related separation process, the mass spectrum is actually the average intensities of all the mass during the sampling time. Recently I am thinking how to process such data via xcms.
Supposing we have data from 1 min sampling and we want to get the mass spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using xcms offline for metabolomics study</title>
      <link>/en/2017/05/02/using-xcms-offline-for-metabolomics-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/05/02/using-xcms-offline-for-metabolomics-study/</guid>
      <description>XCMS online is preferred for its convenience, especially with Stream. However, the storage is limited and you need to wait for some time to process your data. Actually, almost all of the functions online could be processed offline on local computer. Here I will show you some tips about using xcms package locally in R.
Optimized Parameters Most of the users like xcms online because they have optimized parameters for different instruments and you could directly choose them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for local installation of MetaboAnalyst on Windows</title>
      <link>/en/2017/03/29/metaboanalyst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2017/03/29/metaboanalyst/</guid>
      <description>I am running Windows 7 to perform metabolomics data analysis(mainly for mscovert). Recently I found MetaboAnalyst could be installed locally. Since some group members really care about their data safety, I just installed MetaboAnalyst on one of group computers. Here is some tips for it:
 Windows 7 is currently not supported by Metaboanalyst, so I use virtualbox to install a 64-bit Ubuntu 16.10.
 For Ubuntu, you need to install a few packages to support both the R and Java environment, also some packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolomics workflow in Rstudio</title>
      <link>/en/2016/08/21/meta-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/2016/08/21/meta-workflow/</guid>
      <description>I have moved to Canada for about three weeks. Now I am a PostDoc in University of Waterloo. I will handle two projects about in silica studies in analytical chemistry. Well, I treated them as another data and modeling-driven interdisciplinary studies.
The first step is building the data analysis envrionment for group members. Since I could set down such envrionment on a super computer with RAM 128 GB, I preferred to use R and xcms for metabolomics data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>